<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcasts on IoT Forge</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/podcasts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcasts on IoT Forge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.129.0</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/podcasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Arduino’s 20th Anniversary to AI-Powered Robotics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250318/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250318/</guid>
      <description>We celebrate Arduino&amp;#39;s 20th anniversary, reflecting on its impact and future. Next, we explore Google DeepMind&amp;#39;s Gemini Robotics project, which is integrating advanced AI into robotic hardware. We then discuss Home Assistant&amp;#39;s major updates: the expanded Music Assistant and official Matter certification, both of which enhance its position in the smart home space. Lastly, we delve into the creative world of circuit bending, where hackers turn everyday devices into unique musical instruments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IoT Evolves: Smarter Hardware, Smarter Networks, Smarter Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250304/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250304/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of IoT Forge Unplugged, we dive into the upgraded ESP32-C2 and where it fits in real-world applications, the latest ESPHome update with expanded audio support, and whether I³C really improves on I²C’s distance limitations. Plus, we explore EdgeAI for predictive maintenance, energy harvesting for Ambient IoT, and how Arduino and Silicon Labs are making Matter and machine learning more accessible. Finally, we break down concurrent multiprotocols — why they matter and who should explore them.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Smart home trends, AI-powered microcontrollers, IoT security, and the evolving cellular IoT market</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250218/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250218/</guid>
      <description>Today, we look into Matter, a universal smart home standard, and compare it with the versatile Home Assistant platform. We also dive into STMicroelectronics&amp;#39; STM32N6 microcontroller, designed to bring AI capabilities to real-time data processing at the edge. Next up, we discuss a massive data breach at Mars Hydro and its implications for IoT security. Finally, we review the current state of the cellular IoT module market, analyzing its growth and challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics and medical, manufacturing and food industries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250203/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250203/</guid>
      <description>For this episode, I want to focus on something more specific in one area, as opposed to covering a wide variety of news. Recently, I came across a couple of news stories and articles about robotics and their role in different areas. I want to highlight three particular cases: medical, manufacturing, and food. And to start a new tradition, every odd episode I will include a few observations from the personal projects I’m working on — stay tuned to learn how to use fewer microcontrollers to make life easier.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CES Highlights &amp; NB-IoT Shift</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250121/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250121/</guid>
      <description>A quick dive into IoT trends! This episode covers CES 2025 highlights, including AI-driven devices, automotive IoT advancements, and connectivity innovations, plus the decline of NB-IoT. Stay updated and inspired!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apple, NVIDIA, and Satellite NB-IoT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250107/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/podcasts/250107/</guid>
      <description>Dive into this episode of IoT Forge Unplugged, where we explore exciting IoT developments! We discuss Apple’s move into Wi-Fi and Bluetooth chips, NVIDIA’s Jetson Orin Nano and its edge computing potential, and groundbreaking satellite NB-IoT trials by Mavenir and Terrestar. Plus, a DIY project idea to control Raspberry Pi GPIOs via Arduino Cloud.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
